Welcome back. How did that go for you?
欢迎回来。你的工作进展如何？
Hopefully that was interesting enough for you to do.
希望这对你来说是足够有趣的事情。
Now let's look at how I would do it.
现在让我们来看看我会怎么做。
So first I'm going to go back to my header file of Capstone Moving component.
首先，我要回到我的Capstone Moving组件的头文件中。
Then under this canStartClimbing, I'm going to add a new function.
然后在canStartClimbing下，我将添加一个新的函数。
So this function is going to return a bool as well.
所以这个函数也将返回一个bool。
I'm going to call it canClimbDownLedge.
我将把它称为canClimbDownLedge。
And I'm going to create a function definition.
然后我将创建一个函数定义。
Place the function under canStartClimbing.
把这个函数放在canStartClimbing下面。
So place it in here.
所以把它放在这里。
And same as above, if we are falling, I'm going to return false.
和上面一样，如果我们正在下降，我将返回false。
Once we get past this if check, I'm going to set up the things we need for doing multiple line traces.
一旦我们通过了这个if检查，我将设置我们需要的东西来进行多线追踪。
So I'm going to first create a const FVector.
所以我将首先创建一个const FVector。
I'm going to call this one component location.
我将把这个称为一个组件的位置。
So it's going to equal to this updated component getComponentLocation.
所以它将等于这个更新的组件getComponentLocation。
Then create another one and I'm going to call this one component forward.
然后再创建一个，我将调用这一个组件的前进。
And I'm going to get hold of the forward vector in here.
我将在这里获得向前的矢量。
Third one, I'm going to get hold of the down vector.
第三个，我将得到向下的向量。
So it's going to equal to this updated component getUpVector.
所以它将等于这个更新的组件getUpVector。
And I'm going to inverse this.
然后我将反转这个。
Alright, for this condition check, I like to do it through two line traces.
好了，对于这个条件检查，我喜欢通过两条线追踪来做。
So the first line trace, I'm going to create a new const FVector.
所以第一条线迹，我将创建一个新的常量FVector。
I'm going to call this one walkable surface trace start.
我打算把这个叫做可行走的表面追踪开始。
So this trace is for tracing when down and up we are on a walkable surface.
所以这条轨迹是用来追踪我们在可行走表面上向下和向上的时间。
And it's going to equal to this component location plus this component forward multiplied with some trace offset.
它将等于这个组件的位置加上这个组件的前向乘以一些轨迹偏移。
And I like to create another member variable for that.
我喜欢为它创建另一个成员变量。
So this is something we can adjust later inside the footprint.
因此，我们可以在以后的脚印中调整这个变量。
So I'm going to go back to my header file and scroll down to this BP variable.
所以我将回到我的头文件，向下滚动到这个BP变量。
And I'm going to copy this new property along with the float pasted in here.
我要把这个新的属性和粘贴在这里的float一起复制过来。
I'm going to change its name to climb down walkable surface trace offset.
我将把它的名字改为 "爬下的可行走表面追踪偏移"。
And I'm going to give it a hot code value of 200 units.
而我要给它一个200单位的热码值。
We'll need to tweak this later. And I'm going to copy this float and paste it in here.
我们稍后将需要调整这个。我将复制这个浮动值并将其粘贴在这里。
Alright, this is our trace start and we'll need a trace end.
好了，这是我们的追踪起点，我们需要一个追踪终点。
So copy this const FVector and I'm going to call this one walkable surface trace end.
所以复制这个常量FVector，我打算把这个叫做可行走表面的追踪终点。
It's going to equal to this trace start plus this down vector multiplied with 100 units.
它将等于这个追踪起点加上这个向下的矢量，再乘以100个单位。
Alright, I have the start, the end.
好了，我有了起点和终点。
I'm going to call the function do line trace single by object and pass in this start, the end.
我将调用函数do line trace single by object并传入这个开始和结束。
And pass in true for now. I do want to see the debug shape.
现在传入true。我确实想看一下调试形状。
And store the return result of this inside of a local variable.
并将返回的结果存储在一个局部变量中。
So it's going to be an F head result. I'm going to call this walkable surface hit.
所以它将会是一个F头的结果。我将把这个称为可行走的表面撞击。
Alright, that's my first line trace and I like to do the second line trace.
好了，这是我的第一行跟踪，我喜欢做第二行跟踪。
So it's going to be another const FVector. Duplicate this.
所以它将是另一个常量FVector。复制这个。
And this line trace is for detecting the ledge.
这条线迹是用来检测壁架的。
So I'm going to call this one ledge trace start and it's going to equal to this walkable surface hit dot trace start.
所以我打算把这个叫做壁架追踪开始，它将等于这个可行走的表面打点追踪开始。
And plus this component forward multiplied with the trace offset.
再加上这个组件向前乘以跟踪偏移量。
And for that I like to create another member variable.
为此，我喜欢创建另一个成员变量。
So go back to my header file. I'm going to copy this U property and paste it in here.
所以请回到我的头文件中。我要复制这个U属性并把它粘贴到这里。
And I'm going to call this one climb down ledge trace offset.
我将把这个称为 "爬下台阶的偏移量"。
And I'm going to give it a heart code value of 50 units.
我将给它一个50单位的心脏代码值。
And for this one I think I'm going to lower it down to 100 units.
对于这个，我想我要把它降到100单位。
Alright, and I'm going to copy the name of it, paste it to my CPP file.
好的，我将复制它的名字，把它粘贴到我的CPP文件中。
So this is my new line trace start and I'll need a new end.
所以这是我的新线迹开始，我需要一个新的结束。
So I'm going to call this one ledge trace end.
所以我将把这个称为壁架追踪的终点。
And it's going to equal to this ledge trace start plus this down vector multiplied with a heart code value of 300 units.
它将等于这个台阶跟踪的起点加上这个向下的矢量，再乘以300单位的心码值。
You'll know what I'm doing once you see the debug shape.
一旦你看到调试的形状，你就会知道我在做什么。
And I'm going to call the function again.
我将再次调用这个函数。
So copy this, paste it in here, pass in this trace start, the end.
所以复制这个，把它粘贴到这里，传入这个跟踪的开始和结束。
And I'm going to store the return result of this inside of an overhead result.
我将把这个返回的结果存储在一个开销结果里面。
So copy this, paste it in here. I'm going to call this ledge trace hit.
所以复制这个，把它粘贴到这里。我将把这个称为 "壁架追踪命中"。
Alright, next thing I'm going to do an if check.
好的，接下来我将做一个if检查。
So if the first hit result, the B blocking hit is true and the second hit result, the B blocking hit is false.
所以，如果第一次命中的结果，B挡的命中为真，第二次命中的结果，B挡的命中为假。
So this means we are indeed on a walkable surface and we do have a ledge in front of us.
所以这意味着我们确实在一个可行走的表面上，而且我们前面确实有一个壁架。
If both of these conditions are true, I'm going to return true in this function.
如果这两个条件都是真的，我将在这个函数中返回真。
And at the end of this function, I'm going to return false.
而在这个函数的结尾，我将返回false。
And that's pretty much it.
这就差不多了。
Now I'm going to call this function.
现在我将调用这个函数。
So copy this can climb down ledge and scroll up to this toggle climbing.
因此，复制这个可以爬下的窗台，并向上滚动到这个切换攀登的功能。
So if this can start climbing is false.
因此，如果这个可以开始攀爬是假的。
So in the else case, I'm going to check else if this can climb down ledge is true.
所以在else情况下，我将检查else是否这个可以爬下壁架是真的。
If it is, I'm going to print a message to the screen that says can climb down and change its color.
如果是的话，我要在屏幕上打印一条信息，说可以往下爬，并改变其颜色。
To cyan.
为青色。
This in key give it a value of one.
这个键给它的值是1。
And if this condition is false, I'm going to print another message that says cannot climb down, change the color to red.
如果这个条件是假的，我将打印另一条信息，说不能爬下去，把颜色改成红色。
And there's one more thing that I want to do.
还有一件事我想做。
So this function will only be called once the climb action key is pressed.
所以这个函数只有在按下爬升动作键时才会被调用。
But since I want to see the debug shape in here, I'm first going to call the function inside of this component for now.
但是因为我想在这里看到调试的形状，所以我首先要在这个组件中调用这个函数。
So copy it and paste it in here.
所以复制它并粘贴到这里。
All right. I'm going to try to compile.
好的。我将尝试编译。
I have a successful compile. I'm going to launch my editor back.
我有一个成功的编译。我将启动我的编辑器回来。
All right. Go back to my editor. I'm going to press play.
好的。回到我的编辑器。我将按下播放键。
And you can see I have two line traces in front of the character.
你可以看到我在角色前面有两条线的痕迹。
Now, if I press F, it says cannot climb down.
现在，如果我按F，它说不能往下爬。
And if I try to climb up in here and move up and I'm going to go to here and press F.
如果我试着在这里爬上去，然后向上爬，我就去这里按F。
So here it says cannot climb down.
所以这里说不能往下爬。
Right now, I think the first line trace is too far away from the character.
现在，我认为第一行的痕迹离人物太远了。
I'm going to fix that.
我要去解决这个问题。
So go back to this climb system, open this character blueprint and collect this custom moving component.
所以回到这个攀爬系统，打开这个角色蓝图，收集这个自定义移动组件。
I'm going to adjust this climbed out walkable surface trace offset.
我要调整这个攀爬出来的可行走表面的轨迹偏移。
So change it from 100 to 50. And I'm going to see what this looks like.
所以把它从100改为50。我要看看这看起来像什么。
So press play again.
所以再按一次播放。
All right. I think this looks more reasonable.
好的。我认为这看起来更合理。
So in situations like this, if I press F, it says cannot climb down because we have two valid hit results.
所以在这样的情况下，如果我按F，它说不能爬下去，因为我们有两个有效的命中结果。
And if I go to here and I press F, it says cannot climb down.
而如果我走到这里，按F，它说不能爬下去。
So if you want to rule out this situation, right now, my second line trace has a length of 300 units.
所以，如果你想排除这种情况，现在，我的第二条线迹的长度是300单位。
If I want to climb down in surface like this, I just need to lower its height.
如果我想在这样的表面爬下来，我只需要降低它的高度。
All right. I'm going to test another situation.
好了。我现在要测试另一种情况。
So climb up, go to a surface like this and press F.
所以爬上去，到这样的表面，按F。
It says can climb down.
它说可以爬下来。
So we have valid hit for the first line trace and we don't have a hit for the second line trace.
所以我们对第一条线的跟踪是有效的，而对第二条线的跟踪则是无效的。
Great.
很好。
This is working and I'm going to go to a higher surface in here.
这是在工作，我要去这里的一个更高的表面。
Then press F.
然后按F。
Here it says can climb down.
这里说可以爬下去。
And now it says cannot climb down.
而现在它说不能爬下去。
The reason why I want to do two line traces is so in some edge cases, we can move our character to be very close to the edge.
我之所以要做两条线的追踪是为了在一些边缘情况下，我们可以把我们的角色移动到非常接近边缘的地方。
So something like this.
所以像这样的东西。
And now if I press F, we shouldn't be able to climb down.
现在如果我按下F，我们应该不能爬下去了。
So that's what the first line trace is here for.
所以这就是第一行追踪的作用。
What was your solution like?
你的解决方案是什么样子的？
Was yours similar to mine or did you come up with a much better one?
你的方案和我的相似吗？还是你想出了一个更好的方案？
Do share your solution in the description channel and I'll see you in the next lecture.
请在描述频道中分享你的解决方案，我们将在下一次讲座中见。
Thank you.
谢谢你。